metmuseum.org 2015-06-28

# Privacy Policy | The Metropolitan Museum of Art

The Metropolitan Museum of Art is committed to protecting the privacy of our visitors. This privacy policy governs the way we collect and use information both online and offline, including at www.metmuseum.org and its subdomains, including websites accessed through your mobile devices as well as downloadable mobile applications ("Websites"). A link to this policy is included in the footer information on every page of the Websites. Your use of the Websites or provision of personal information to the Museum as described below constitutes your agreement to the terms of this privacy policy.

* * *

  * How We Collect and Use the Information You Provide
  * Cookies
  * When You Register
  * When You Make a Donation or Purchase a Membership
  * When You Shop in The Met Store
  * When You Purchase Tickets to an Event
  * When You Complete a Survey
  * Blogs
  * Email Communication
  * Emailing the Museum
  * Third-Party Service Providers
  * Share Features
  * Children Under Thirteen Years of Age
  * Data Security
  * Changes to the Privacy Policy
  * Contact Us

* * *

**How We Collect and Use the Information You Provide**

We collect and use the information you provide to personalize the Websites so that we can better meet your needs, fulfill your online order, facilitate customer service, and inform you of the Museum's products and promotional offers. Our collection and use of visitor information varies with the type of visit or transaction. For details about each transaction type, see When You Register, When You Make a Donation or Purchase a Membership, When You Shop in The Met Store, When You Purchase Tickets to an Event, or When You Complete a Survey. As described below, your privacy rights allow you to exclude your personally identifiable information (to "opt-out") from disclosure to third parties for marketing purposes.

* * *

**Cookies and Pixel Tags**

The Websites use technologies such as "cookies" and "pixel tags" to improve the functioning of our website and your experience. Cookies are small data files that are automatically sent to your browser from a Web server and stored on your computer's hard drive. Cookies enable us to remember what items are in your shopping cart, and to personalize your experience. "Pixel tags" are tiny graphical images embedded in emails or webpages. Pixel tags are used to determine what parts of a website a visitor has viewed, or whether an email was successfully opened. These technologies do not contain any personal information about you; they are used to gather information to analyze traffic to the Websites, to improve our content and navigation, to enhance our marketing efforts, to personalize your experience, and to provide online display advertising tailored to your interests based on your online behavior. To opt out of this advertising provided by The Met Store, visit [here](http://dtmc.metmuseum.org/adinfo/adchoices_fpc.html?cid=2118&cname=Met%20Museum&cmagic=92bbd3&clogo=met_museum.png).

The Museum also works with third-party marketing partners who use technologies such as cookies and pixel tags on our behalf. For details, see Third-Party Service Providers.

You may choose to set your browser so that it does not accept cookies. Most areas of the Websites will function without cookies, but cookies are required if you wish to register, sign in, or place items in your shopping bag. For an optimal experience with our site, we recommend that you allow cookies.

* * *

**When You Register**

You may use the Websites without registering or submitting any personal information. However, registration in MyMet enables you to maintain your contact information and sign up for exclusive online features such as MyMet, My Membership, free email newsletters, and a press account for accredited media. Registration in The Met Store provides access to features such as your order history and address book.

If you choose to register in any of these areas of the Websites, you will be asked to provide personal information that may include a username and password, your name, email address, postal address, telephone number, and your Membership number, if applicable. We store this information, along with your other preferences, on a secure server so that you need not re-enter it when you return to the Websites. When registering in MyMet, if you select "Stay logged in," your information will be displayed automatically the next time you return to MyMet. You may review or change your account information in MyMet or The Met Store at any time.

* * *

**When You Make a Donation or Purchase a Membership**

The Museum will ask you to provide personal information that is necessary to process and service your donation or Membership online, which may include your name, billing and shipping addresses, telephone number, email address, and credit card number. Your credit card information will be temporarily stored on a secure server and used only for processing your online transaction. We will retain the information you provided for our records, and to facilitate customer service. The Museum never shares the information you provide when making a donation or purchasing a Membership online, through the mail, in person, or by telephone, with third parties for marketing purposes, except as required by law. 

In certain cases, you may be asked for additional information required to complete and service your request, such as the names of your children when joining the Met Family Circle. (See Children Under Thirteen Years of Age.) 

* * *

**When You Shop in The Met Store**

The Met Store will ask you to provide personal information necessary to fulfill your online order or catalogue request, which may include your name, billing and shipping addresses, telephone number, and credit card number. This is the same information requested when you place an order by telephone or through the mail. For online orders or catalogue requests, we also require your email address so that you can receive order, shipping, and other transaction-related emails, and so that we can communicate with you if we have difficulty processing your order or request. When you make a purchase, your credit card information will be stored temporarily on a secure server, and we will retain the personal information you provided with your order for our records, to facilitate customer service, and to inform you of our products and promotional offers. If you are a registered customer at The Met Store, your credit card information will be saved for the next time you shop with us, or you may select "Please do not save my payment details" on the Order Review page to opt out of this feature.

When you make an online purchase or request a catalogue from The Met Store, we may share the information you provide, such as your name and your postal address, with other reputable organizations and companies whose products and services might interest you. Please note that the privacy policies of these organizations and companies may differ from ours. If you prefer not to have your personal information shared with third parties for marketing purposes, or would like to be removed from our mailing list, please contact us:

**On the Website:**  
By unchecking the box labeled "On occasion, I would like to receive information from companies carefully screened by The Met Store whose products and services may be of interest to me" that appears on the Billing Address page of The Met Store shopping registration process.

**By Email:**  

**By Phone:**  
Call our toll-free number 1-800-662-3397 (US and Canada) Monday–Friday, 9:00 a.m. to 5:00 p.m. ET, except public holidays. From other locations, please dial the appropriate United States access code, then 212-731-1498.

**By Mail:**  
The Metropolitan Museum of Art Store  
Customer Service Department  
66-26 Metropolitan Avenue  
Middle Village, New York 11381-0001  
United States of America

If you are placing an order by mail, you may check the appropriate box on the catalogue order form to indicate your preference.

We may also share your personal information with third-party service marketing partners to personalize your shopping experience on our and other websites. For details, see Third-Party Service Providers.

Subsequent to your online purchase, you may receive email communications (where you will have an opportunity to opt-out of further communications) requesting that your rate or review a product. When you rate or review a product from The Met Store, using the Customer Ratings and Reviews service, you will be asked to enter your email address so that we can contact you in relation to your review. For details, see [Customer Ratings and Reviews Terms of Use](https://store.metmuseum.org/page/crrtermsofuse).

As part of our commitment to your privacy, The Met Store supports and adheres to the guidelines and practices of the [Direct Marketing Association's Commitment to Consumer Choice](https://dmachoice.org/).

* * *

**When You Purchase Tickets to an Event**

The Museum will ask you to provide personal information necessary to fulfill your online ticket order or brochure request, which may include your name, billing and shipping addresses, telephone number, and credit card number. This is the same information requested when you place a ticket order by telephone or in person at the Museum. For online ticket orders or brochure requests, we also require your email address so that you can receive order, shipping, event, or other transaction-related emails, and so that we can communicate with you if we have difficulty processing your ticket order or request. When you purchase tickets, your credit card information will be stored temporarily on a secure server, and we will retain the personal information you provided with your order for our records, to facilitate customer service, and to inform you of Museum-related programs and offerings.

When you purchase tickets or request a brochure, we may share the information you provide, such as your name and your postal address, with other reputable organizations and companies whose programs and services might interest you. Please note that the privacy policies of these organizations and companies may differ from ours. If you prefer not to have your personal information shared with third parties for marketing purposes, or would like to be removed from our mailing list, please contact us:

**On the Website:**  
By unchecking the box labeled "On occasion, I would like to receive information from third parties whose products and services may be of interest to me."

**By Email:**  

**By Phone:**  
212-570-3750

**By Mail:**  
The Metropolitan Museum of Art  
Concerts & Lectures Department  
1000 Fifth Avenue  
New York, New York 10028-0198  
United States of America

**In Person:**  
If you are placing a ticket order in person at the Museum, you may indicate your preference to Museum staff when purchasing your tickets.

We may also share your personal information with third-party service marketing partners to personalize your shopping experience on our and other websites. For details, see Third-Party Service Providers.

* * *

**When You Complete a Survey**

The Museum occasionally asks for feedback and publishes surveys on the Websites or through a reputable third-party service provider. Your participation in these surveys is on a voluntary and anonymous basis, unless otherwise specified. We use the survey responses to improve our understanding of you, our visitors, and to determine how best to serve your needs. Information collected in these surveys is never sold, rented, or shared with third parties for marketing purposes. 

* * *

**Blogs**

We welcome your participation on our blogs. An email address is required to post comments. The Museum will not use these email addresses in any way, unless permission to do so is specifically requested and granted. We will not share these email addresses with any third parties for marketing purposes. 

* * *

**Email Communication**

The Museum regularly sends email to visitors to the Websites. Email recipients may opt out at any time by following the "unsubscribe" instructions included in the email message. MyMet registrants may subscribe or unsubscribe at any time by changing their email preferences online. 

* * *

**Emailing the Museum**

If you email the Museum, any message, material, business information, ideas, concepts, or other information sent to the Museum by email will be treated as non-confidential and non-proprietary. 

* * *

**Third-Party Service Providers**

The Museum engages reputable third-party vendors in order to help us manage the Websites, process transactions, better respond to the needs of our visitors, and enhance our marketing efforts. This includes third-party marketing partners who serve advertisements across the Internet and sometimes on the Websites on the Museum's behalf. They may use information about your visits to the Websites and other sites to personalize advertisements for goods and services. The Museum may also share your personal information—including your name, address, email address, as well as a record of any transactions you conduct with us on our website or offline—with a third-party advertising partner and its service providers in order to deliver to you advertisements tailored to your interests on certain websites. Our advertising partner will make the data we provide anonymous. Although this website does not respond to a browser's "Do Not Track" signal, you may opt-out of interest-based advertising. To learn more about the use of this information and about advertising tailored to your interests by third parties, or to opt out, visit the [Network Advertising Initiative](http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/).

The Museum requires its vendors to maintain the confidentiality of the information to which they are provided access, and restricts these vendors from using or disclosing the information in any way without express authorization by the Museum.

* * *

**Share Features**

The Museum uses third-party tools to give you easy ways to share our content with others. The information you provide when using these tools is subject to the third parties' privacy policies.

* * *

**Children Under Thirteen Years of Age**

The Museum takes special care to protect the safety and privacy of children. We do not knowingly collect personal information from children under thirteen years of age. 

* * *

**Data Security**

The Museum makes every reasonable effort to ensure the security of transactions that occur on the Websites. To maintain data accuracy, prevent unauthorized access, and ensure the correct use of information, we have put appropriate physical, electronic, and administrative procedures in place to safeguard and secure the information we collect online. We utilize SSL (Secure Socket Layer) technology, which encrypts our visitors' credit card numbers, names, and addresses. The metmuseum.org site is also a VeriSign Secure Site and PCI DSS (Payment Card Industry Data Security Standard) compliant, and store.metmuseum.org is a GeoTrust Secure Site, and PCI DSS (Payment Card Industry Data Security Standard) compliant, which ensures security and protection of sensitive customer credit card information. 

Please be advised that when placing an online order through The Met Store, your personal data will be protected in accordance with United States law but may not be at the same level of protection as is legally required in the European Union. If you are shopping with us and your billing or shipping address is in the European Union, you will be asked to consent to The Met Store's [EU Data Protection Disclosure](http://store.metmuseum.org/page/EUterms&layout=empty) upon checkout.

* * *

**Changes to the Privacy Policy**

The Metropolitan Museum of Art may revise this privacy policy at any time. Check here often for updates.

* * *

**Contact Us**

If you have any questions regarding this privacy policy, please contact the Museum's Digital Media Department:

Digital Media Department   
The Metropolitan Museum of Art   
1000 Fifth Avenue  
New York, New York 10028-0198   
Telephone: 212-650-2550   
Email: [privacypolicy@metmuseum.org](mailto:privacypolicy@metmuseum.org)

This policy was last updated September 3, 2014.
